const quizQuestions = [

    {
  
      question: "Which of the following is generally used for performing tasks like creating the structure of the relations, deleting relation?",
  
      options: ["DML","Query","Relational Schema","DDL"],
  
      correctAnswer: "DDL"
  
    },
  
    {
  
      question: "Which of the following provides the ability to query information from the database and insert tuples into, delete tuples from, and modify tuples in the database?",
  
      options: ["DML", "DDL", "Query", "Relational Schema"],
  
      correctAnswer: "DML"
  
    },
  
    {
      question: " Which of the following can be considered as the maximum size that is supported by FAT?",
  
      options: ["8GB", "4GB", "4TB", "None of the above"],
  
      correctAnswer: "4GB"
  
    },
  
    {
  
       question: "Which of the following can be considered as the maximum size that is supported by NTFS?",
  
       options: ["4GB", "16TB", "64TB", "8TB"],
  
      correctAnswer: "4GB"
  
    },
  
    {
  
       question: "A huge collection of the information or data accumulated form several different sources is known as ________:",
  
       options: ["Data Management", "Data Mining", "Data Warehouse", "Both B and C"],
  
       correctAnswer: "Data Warehouse"
  
    },
  
    {
  
      question:"Which of the following can be used to extract or filter the data & information from the data warehouse?",
  
      options:["Data redundancy","Data recovery tool","Data mining","Both B and C"],
  
      correctAnswer:"Data mining"
  
    },
  
    {
  
        question:"Which one of the following refers to the copies of the same data (or information) occupying the memory space at multiple places.",
  
        options:["Data Repository","Data Inconsistency","Data Mining","Data Redundancy"],
  
        correctAnswer:"Data Redundancy"
  
      },
  
    {
  
      questio:"Which one of the following refers to the 'data about data'?",
  
        options:["Directory","Sub Data","Warehouse","Meta Data"],
  
        correctAnswer:"Meta Data"
  
      },
  
    {
  
      question:"Which of the following refers to the level of data abstraction that describes exactly how the data actually stored?",
  
      options:["Conceptual Level","Physical Level","File Level","Logical Level"],
  
         correctAnswer:"Physical Level"
  
       },
  
    {
  
       question:" To which of the following the term 'DBA' referred?",
  
      options:["Data Bank Administrator","Database Administrator","Data Administrator","None of the above"],
  
         correctAnswer:"Database Administrator"
  
      },
  
    {
  
      question:" In general, a file is basically a collection of all related______.",
  
      options:["Rows & Columns","Fields","Database","Records"],
  
      correctAnswer:"Records"
  
      },
  
    {
  
      question:"Rows of a relation are known as the _______.",
  
      options:["Degree","Tuples","Entity","All of the above"],
  
      correctAnswer:"All of the above"
  
      },
  
    {
  
      question:"Which of the following refers to the number of tuples in a relation?",
  
      options:["Entity","Column","Cardinality","None of the above"],
  
      correctAnswer:"Cardinality"
  
      },
  
    {
  
      question:"Which one of the following is a type of Data Manipulation Command?",
  
      options:["Create","char","Delete","All of the above"],
  
      correctAnswer:"Delete"
  
      },
  
    {
  
      question:"Which of the following command is a type of Data Definition language command?",
  
      options:["Create","Update","Delete","Merge"],
  
      correctAnswer:"Create"
  
      },
  
      {
  
          question:"Which of the following is a top-down approach in which the entity's higher level can be divided into two lower sub-entities?",
  
          options:["Aggregation","Generalization","Specialization","All of the above"],
  
          correctAnswer:"Specialization"
  
        },
  
      {
  
        question:" In which one of the following, the multiple lower entities are grouped (or combined) together to form a single higher-level entity?",
  
          options:["Specialization","Generalization","Aggregation","None of the above"],
  
          correctAnswer:"Generalization"
  
      },
  
      {
  
      question:"In a relation database, every tuples divided into the fields are known as the______.",
  
      options:["Queries","Domains","Relations","All of the above"],
  
           correctAnswer:"Domains"
  
        },
  
      {
  
      question:"In the relational table, which of the following can also be represented by the term 'attribute'?",
  
      options:["Entity","Row","Column","Both B &C"],
  
           correctAnswer:"Column"
  
        },
  
      {
  
      question:"Which of the following refers to the number of attributes in a relation?",
  
      options:["Degree","Row","Column","All of the above"],
  
      correctAnswer:"Degree"
  
      },
  
      {
  
      question:"Which one of the following command is used to delete the existing row in a table?",
  
      options:["Delete","Update","Insert","none"],
  
      correctAnswer:"Delete"
  
      },
  
      {
  
      question:"Which of the following commands is used to save any transaction permanently into the database?",
  
      options:["Commit","Rollback","Savepoint","None of the above"],
  
      correctAnswer:"Commit"
  
      },
  
      {
  
      question:"Which one of the following commands is used for removing (or deleting) a relation forms the SQL database?",
  
      options:["Delete","Drop","Remove","All of the above"],
  
        correctAnswer:"Delete"
  
      },
  
      {
  
      question:"Which one of the following commands is used to restore the database to the last committed state?",
  
      options:["Savepoint","Rollback","Commit","Both A & B"],
  
        correctAnswer:"Rollback"
  
        },
  
        {
  
            question:"The database management system can be considered as the collection of ______ that enables us to create and maintain the database.",
  
            options:["Translators","Programs","Keys","Language activity"],
  
            correctAnswer:"Programs"
  
          },
  
        {
  
          question:"The term 'DFD' stands for?",
  
            options:["Data file diagram","Data flow document","Data flow diagram","None of the above"],
  
            correctAnswer:"Data flow diagram"
  
        },
  
        {
  
        question:"Which of the following refers collection of the information stored in a database at a specific time?",
  
        options:["Independence","Instance of the database","Schema","Data domain"],
  
             correctAnswer:"Instance of the database"
  
          },
  
        {
  
        question:"Which one of the following refers to the total view of the database content?",
  
        options:["Conceptual view","Physical view","Internal view","External view"],
  
             correctAnswer:"Conceptual view"
  
          },
  
        {
  
        question:"The architecture of a database can be viewed as the ________",
  
        options:["One level","Two-level","Three-level","Four level"],
  
        correctAnswer:"Three-level"
  
        },
  
        {
  
        question:"In the relation model, the relation are generally termed as ________",
  
        options:["Tuples","Attributes","Rows","Tables"],
  
        correctAnswer:"Tables"
  
        },
  
        {
  
        question:"Which of the following keys is generally used to represents the relationships between the tables?",
  
        options:["Primary key","Foreign key","Secondary key","None of the above"],
  
        correctAnswer:"Foreign key"
  
        },
  
        {
  
        question:"Which of the following levels is considered as the level closed to the end-users?",
  
        options:["Internal Level","External Level","Conceptual Level","Physical Level"],
  
          correctAnswer:"External Level"
  
        },
  
        {
  
        question:"A computer security protocol for logging-in can be considered as the example of the ______ component of an information system.",
  
        options:["Data","Software","Procedure","Hardware"],
  
          correctAnswer:"Procedure"
  
          },
  
          {
  
              question:"Which one of the following keyword is used to find out the number of values in a column?",
  
              options:["TOTAL","COUNT","SUM","ADD"],
  
              correctAnswer:"COUNT"
  
            },
  
          {
  
            question:"Which one of the following commands is used to modify a column inside a table?",
  
              options:["Drop","Update","Alter","Set"],
  
              correctAnswer:"Alter"
  
          },
  
          {
  
          question:"Who created the first DBMS?",
  
          options:["Edgar Frank Codd","Charles Bachman","Charles Babbage","Sharon B. Codd"],
  
               correctAnswer:"Charles Bachman"
  
            },
  
          {
  
          question:"Which of the following is not a type of database?",
  
          options:["Hierarchical","Network","Distributed","Decentralized"],
  
               correctAnswer:"Decentralized"
  
            },
  
          {
  
          question:"In which of the following formats data is stored in the database management system?",
  
          options:["Image","Text","Table","Graph"],
  
          correctAnswer:"Table"
  
          },
  
          {
  
          question:"Which of the following is not an example of DBMS?",
  
          options:["MySQL","Microsoft Acess","IBM DB2","Google"],
  
          correctAnswer:"false"
  
          },
  
          {
  
          question:"Which of the following is a component of the DBMS?",
  
          options:["Data","Data Languages","Data Manager","All of the above"],
  
          correctAnswer:"All of the above"
  
          },
  
          {
  
          question:"Which of the following is known as a set of entities of the same type that share same properties, or attributes?",
  
          options:["Relation set","Tuples","Entity set","Entity Relation model"],
  
            correctAnswer:"Entity set"
  
    },
  
   {
  
      question:"What is information about data called?",
  
      options:["Hyper data","Tera data","Meta data","Relations"],
  
      correctAnswer:"Meta data"
  
    },
  
    {
  
    question:"The ability to query data, as well as insert, delete, and alter tuples, is offered by ____________",
  
    options:["TCL","DCL","DDL","DML"],
  
    correctAnswer:"DML"
  
     },
  
     {
  
     question:" ______________ is a set of one or more attributes taken collectively to uniquely identify a record.",
  
     options:["Primary Key","Foreign key","Super key","Candidate key"],
  
     correctAnswer:"Super key"
  
      },
  
      {
  
      question:"Which command is used to remove a relation from an SQL?",
  
      options:["Drop table","Delete","Purge","Remove"],
  
      correctAnswer:"Drop table"
  
       },
  
  
  
   {
  
      question:"_________________ operations do not preserve non-matched tuples.",
  
      options: ["Left outer join", "Inner join", "Natural join", "Right outer join"],
  
      correctAnswer: "Inner join"
  
    },
  
    {
  
      question: "After groups have been established, SQL applies predicates in the ___________ clause, allowing aggregate functions to be used.",
  
      options: ["Where", "Having", "Group by", "With"],
  
      correctAnswer: "Having"
  
    },
  
    {
  
       question:"Which of the following is not the utility of DBMS?",
  
       options: ["Backup", "Data Loading", "Process Organization", "File organization"],
  
       correctAnswer: "Process Organization"
  
    },
  
    {
  
      question:"Which of the following is the best way to represent the attributes in a large db?",
  
      options: ["Dot representation", "Concatenation", "Relational-and", "All of the mentioned"],
  
      correctAnswer: "Concatenation"
  
     },
  
     {
  
       question:"Which of the following functions construct histograms and use buckets for ranking?",
  
       options: ["Ntil()", "Newtil()", "Rank()", "All of the mentioned"],
  
       correctAnswer: "Ntil()"
  
     },
  
     {
  
        question: "Which of the following is known as the process of viewing cross-tab with a fixed value of one attribute?",
  
        options: ["Dicing", "Pivoting", "Slicing", "Both Pivoting and Dicing"],
  
        correctAnswer: "Slicing"
  
     },
  
     {
  
      question: "For designing a normal RDBMS which of the following normal form is considered adequate?",
  
      options: ["4NF", "3NF", "2NF", "5NF"],
  
      correctAnswer: "3NF"
  
     },
  
     {
  
      question: "The oldest DB model is _______________",
  
      options: ["Network", "Physical", "Hierarchical", "Relational"],
  
      correctAnswer: "Hierarchical"
  
     },
  
     {
  
      question: "A major goal of the db system is to minimize the number of block transfers between the disk and memory. Which of the following helps in achieving this goal??",
  
      options: [ "Secondary storage", "Storage","Catalog", "Buffer"],
  
      correctAnswer: "Buffer"
  
     },
  
     {
  
      question: "A view of database that appears to an application program is known as",
  
      options: ["Schema","Subschema","Virtual table","Index Table"],
  
      correctAnswer: "Subschema"
  
     },
  
     {
  
       question: "Which operation is used to extract specified columns from a table?",
  
       options: ["Project","Join","Extract","Substitute"],
  
       correctAnswer: "Project"
  
      },
  
     {
  
       question: "Relations produced from E - R Model will always be in ________.",
  
       options: ["1 NF","2 NF","3 NF","4 NF"],
  
       correctAnswer: "1 NF"
  
      },
  
      {
  
        question: "Consider the relation R (ABCDE): FD = { A → B, B → C, C → D, D → E} Find out the highest normal form.",
  
        options: ["1 NF","2 NF","3 NF","BCNF"],
  
        correctAnswer: "2 NF"
  
      },
  
      {
  
        question: "__________ rules used to limit the volume of log information that has to be handled and processed in the event of system failure involving the loss of volatile information.",
  
        options: ["Write-ahead log","Check-pointing","Log buffer","Thomas"],
  
        correctAnswer: "Check-pointing"
  
      },
  
      {
  
        question: "Which of the following RAID level provides the highest Data Transfer Rate (Read/Write)",
  
        options: ["RAID 1","RAID 3","RAID 4","RAID 5"],
  
        correctAnswer: "RAID 1"
  
      },	
      {
  
        question: "Which of the following is the highest isolation level in transaction management?",
  
        options: ["Serializable","Repeated Read","Committed Read","Uncommitted Read"],
  
        correctAnswer: "Serializable"
  
      },	
      {
  
        question: "Which of the following RAID level provides the highest Data Transfer Rate (Read/Write)",
  
        options: ["RAID 1","RAID 3","RAID 4","RAID 5"],
  
        correctAnswer: "RAID 1"
  
      },	
      {
  
        question: "Which of the following RAID level provides the highest Data Transfer Rate (Read/Write)",
  
        options: ["RAID 1","RAID 3","RAID 4","RAID 5"],
  
        correctAnswer: "RAID 1"
  
      },	
      {
  
        question: "Which of the following RAID level provides the highest Data Transfer Rate (Read/Write)",
  
        options: ["RAID 1","RAID 3","RAID 4","RAID 5"],
  
        correctAnswer: "RAID 1"
  
      },	
      {
  
        question: "Which of the following RAID level provides the highest Data Transfer Rate (Read/Write)",
  
        options: ["RAID 1","RAID 3","RAID 4","RAID 5"],
  
        correctAnswer: "RAID 1"
  
      },	
      {
  
        question: "Which of the following RAID level provides the highest Data Transfer Rate (Read/Write)",
  
        options: ["RAID 1","RAID 3","RAID 4","RAID 5"],
  
        correctAnswer: "RAID 1"
  
      },	
      {
  
        question: "Which of the following RAID level provides the highest Data Transfer Rate (Read/Write)",
  
        options: ["RAID 1","RAID 3","RAID 4","RAID 5"],
  
        correctAnswer: "RAID 1"
  
      },	
      {
  
        question: "Which of the following RAID level provides the highest Data Transfer Rate (Read/Write)",
  
        options: ["RAID 1","RAID 3","RAID 4","RAID 5"],
  
        correctAnswer: "RAID 1"
  
      },	
      {
  
        question: "Which of the following RAID level provides the highest Data Transfer Rate (Read/Write)",
  
        options: ["RAID 1","RAID 3","RAID 4","RAID 5"],
  
        correctAnswer: "RAID 1"
  
      },	
      {
  
        question: "Which of the following RAID level provides the highest Data Transfer Rate (Read/Write)",
  
        options: ["RAID 1","RAID 3","RAID 4","RAID 5"],
  
        correctAnswer: "RAID 1"
  
      },	
      {
  
        question: "Which of the following RAID level provides the highest Data Transfer Rate (Read/Write)",
  
        options: ["RAID 1","RAID 3","RAID 4","RAID 5"],
  
        correctAnswer: "RAID 1"
  
      },	
      {
  
        question: "Which of the following RAID level provides the highest Data Transfer Rate (Read/Write)",
  
        options: ["RAID 1","RAID 3","RAID 4","RAID 5"],
  
        correctAnswer: "RAID 1"
  
      },	
      {
  
        question: "Which of the following RAID level provides the highest Data Transfer Rate (Read/Write)",
  
        options: ["RAID 1","RAID 3","RAID 4","RAID 5"],
  
        correctAnswer: "RAID 1"
  
      },	
      {
  
        question: "Which of the following RAID level provides the highest Data Transfer Rate (Read/Write)",
  
        options: ["RAID 1","RAID 3","RAID 4","RAID 5"],
  
        correctAnswer: "RAID 1"
  
      },	
      {
  
        question: "Which of the following RAID level provides the highest Data Transfer Rate (Read/Write)",
  
        options: ["RAID 1","RAID 3","RAID 4","RAID 5"],
  
        correctAnswer: "RAID 1"
  
      },	
      {
  
        question: "Which of the following RAID level provides the highest Data Transfer Rate (Read/Write)",
  
        options: ["RAID 1","RAID 3","RAID 4","RAID 5"],
  
        correctAnswer: "RAID 1"
  
      },	
      {
  
        question: "Which of the following RAID level provides the highest Data Transfer Rate (Read/Write)",
  
        options: ["RAID 1","RAID 3","RAID 4","RAID 5"],
  
        correctAnswer: "RAID 1"
  
      },	
      {
  
        question: "Which of the following RAID level provides the highest Data Transfer Rate (Read/Write)",
  
        options: ["RAID 1","RAID 3","RAID 4","RAID 5"],
  
        correctAnswer: "RAID 1"
  
      },	
      {
  
        question: "Which of the following RAID level provides the highest Data Transfer Rate (Read/Write)",
  
        options: ["RAID 1","RAID 3","RAID 4","RAID 5"],
  
        correctAnswer: "RAID 1"
  
      },	
      {
  
        question: "Which of the following RAID level provides the highest Data Transfer Rate (Read/Write)",
  
        options: ["RAID 1","RAID 3","RAID 4","RAID 5"],
  
        correctAnswer: "RAID 1"
  
      },	
      {
  
        question: "Which of the following RAID level provides the highest Data Transfer Rate (Read/Write)",
  
        options: ["RAID 1","RAID 3","RAID 4","RAID 5"],
  
        correctAnswer: "RAID 1"
  
      },	
      {
  
        question: "Which of the following RAID level provides the highest Data Transfer Rate (Read/Write)",
  
        options: ["RAID 1","RAID 3","RAID 4","RAID 5"],
  
        correctAnswer: "RAID 1"
  
      },	
      {
  
        question: "Which of the following RAID level provides the highest Data Transfer Rate (Read/Write)",
  
        options: ["RAID 1","RAID 3","RAID 4","RAID 5"],
  
        correctAnswer: "RAID 1"
  
      },	
      {
  
        question: "Which of the following RAID level provides the highest Data Transfer Rate (Read/Write)",
  
        options: ["RAID 1","RAID 3","RAID 4","RAID 5"],
  
        correctAnswer: "RAID 1"
  
      },		  
  
  ];
  
  
  
  // Variables to track quiz state
  
  let currentQuestionIndex = 0;
  
  let score = 0;
  
  let timeLeft = 900; // 15 minutes in seconds
  
  let timerInterval;
  
  let selectedQuestions = []; // Array to hold the selected questions
  
  
  
  // Function to start the quiz
  
  function startQuiz() {
  
    // Shuffle and select 20 random questions
  
    selectedQuestions = shuffleArray(quizQuestions).slice(0, 20);
  
  
  
    // Hide the start button and display the first question
  
    document.getElementById("start-button").style.display = "none";
  
    displayQuestion();
  
    startTimer();
  
  }
  
  
  
  // Function to shuffle an array (Fisher-Yates shuffle)
  
  function shuffleArray(array) {
  
    for (let i = array.length - 1; i > 0; i--) {
  
      const j = Math.floor(Math.random() * (i + 1));
  
      [array[i], array[j]] = [array[j], array[i]];
  
    }
  
    return array;
  
  }
  
  
  
  // Function to display a question and its options
  
  function displayQuestion() {
  
    const currentQuestion = selectedQuestions[currentQuestionIndex];
  
    const questionText = document.getElementById("question-text");
  
    const answerButtons = document.getElementById("answer-buttons");
  
  
  
    // Clear previous question and answer options
  
    questionText.innerHTML = "";
  
    answerButtons.innerHTML = "";
  
  
  
    // Display the current question
  
    questionText.innerHTML = currentQuestion.question;
  
  
  
    // Create answer buttons for each option
  
    currentQuestion.options.forEach(option => {
  
      const button = document.createElement("button");
  
      button.innerText = option;
  
      button.classList.add("answer-button");
  
      answerButtons.appendChild(button);
  
  
  
      // Add click event listener to check the answer
  
      button.addEventListener("click", function() {
  
        checkAnswer(option);
  
      });
  
    });
  
  }
  
  
  
  // Function to check the selected answer
  
  function checkAnswer(selectedOption) {
  
    const currentQuestion = selectedQuestions[currentQuestionIndex];
  
  
  
    // Check if the selected answer is correct
  
    if (selectedOption === currentQuestion.correctAnswer) {
  
      score++;
  
    }
  
  
  
    // Move to the next question or end the quiz if all questions are answered
  
    currentQuestionIndex++;
  
  
  
    if (currentQuestionIndex < selectedQuestions.length) {
  
      displayQuestion();
  
    } else {
  
      endQuiz();
  
    }
  
  }
  
  
  
  // function to start the timer
  
  function startTimer() {
  
    timerInterval = setInterval(function() {
  
      timeLeft--;
  
  
  
      // Calculate minutes and seconds
  
      const minutes = Math.floor(timeLeft / 60);
  
      const seconds = timeLeft % 60;
  
  
  
      // Update the timer text
  
      document.getElementById("minutes").textContent = minutes;
  
      document.getElementById("seconds").textContent = seconds < 10 ? "0" + seconds : seconds;
  
  
  
      // End the quiz if time runs out
  
      if (timeLeft <= 0) {
  
        endQuiz();
  
      }
  
    }, 1000);
  
  }
  
  
  
  // Function to end the quiz
  
  function endQuiz() {
  
    // Stop the timer
  
    clearInterval(timerInterval);
  
  
  
    // Calculate the score percentage
  
    const wrongAns = selectedQuestions.length - score;
  
  
  
    // Display the final score
  
    const questionContainer = document.getElementById("question-container");
  
    const resultsWindow = document.getElementById("results-window");
  
  
  
    let message = `
  
      <h2>Quiz Completed!</h2>
  
      <p id="question-text">Your Score       : ${score} out of ${selectedQuestions.length}</p>
  
      <p id="question-text">Correct Answers  : ${score}</p>
  
    `;
  
  
  
    // Check score and show modal if score is less than 5
  
    if (score < 5) {
  
      message += `<p id="question-text">Better luck next time!</p>`;
  
    } else {
  
      message += `<p id="question-text">Congratulations!</p>`;
  
    }
  
  
  
    resultsWindow.innerHTML = message;
  
    resultsWindow.classList.remove("hidden");
  
  }
  
  
  
  // Function to close the results modal
  
  function closeResultsModal() {
  
    const resultsWindow = document.getElementById("results-window");
  
    resultsWindow.classList.add("hidden");
  
  }
  
  
  
  // Add event listener to start the quiz when the start button is clicked
  
  document.getElementById("start-button").addEventListener("click", startQuiz);
  
  
  
  // Event listener to close modal when clicking outside
  
  window.addEventListener("click", function(event) {
  
    const resultsWindow = document.getElementById("results-window");
  
    if (event.target === resultsWindow) {
  
      closeResultsModal();
  
    }
  
  });